Guide to the David Barsamian Collection of Alternative Radio Audio Recordings OH.088
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Kevin Danaher: "Citizen Power," Denver, Colorado, November 7, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0159)
- Ira Chernus: "American Jews and Israel," Boulder, Colorado, November 12, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0160)
- John Stauber and Sheldon Rampton: "Mad Cow USA," Madison, Wisconsin, November 12, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0161)
- Kim Moody: "Workers in a Lean World," New York, New York, November 14, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0164)
- Cornel West: "Black Empowerment," Roxbury, Massachusetts, November 20, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0162)
- Bill Fletcher: "Union Organizing: New Strategies and Tactics," New York, New York, December 12, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0163)
- Jim Hightower: "Politics, Fat Cats and Dead Armadillos," Boulder, Colorado, February 7, 1998 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0165)
- Loretta Ross: "The Global Women's Movement," Madison, Wisconsin, February 7, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0166)
- Lani Guinier: "Educational Opportunity and Democracy," Madison, Wisconsin, February 11, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0167)
- Martin Khor: "The Asian Tiger Economic Meltdown," Washington, D.C., February 11, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0168)
- Dan Baum: "The Drug War Debacle," Boulder, Colorado, February 24, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0169)
- Winona La Duke: "Native American Women and Environmental Struggles," Boulder, Colorado, March 1, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0170)
- Ben Bagdikian: "Navigating the Media," Boulder, Colorado, March 2, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0171)
- Tony Mazzocchi: "Labor and Politics: A New Agenda," Cambridge, Massachusetts, March 4, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0172)
- Noam Chomsky: "The Multilateral Agreement on Investment," Cambridge, Massachusetts, March 6, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0173)
- Kristin Dawkins: "Gene Wars: The Politics of Biotechnology," Boulder, Colorado, March 9, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0174)
- Gilmore, Goldberg and Okazawa-Rey: "The Political Economy of Policing," Boulder, Colorado, March 14, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0175)
- Gilmore, Goldberg and Okazawa-Rey: "The Political Economy of Policing," Boulder, Colorado, March 14, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0278)
- Edward Said: "The Palestinian Future," Houston, Texas, March 26, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0176)
- Ralph Nader: "The Diversion of Discontent," Boulder, Colorado, March 31, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0177)
- Ward Churchill: "Native America: A Little Matter of Genocide," Colorado Springs, Colorado, April 2, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0178)
- Manning Marable: "Democratic Values and Economic Inequality," Portland, Oregon, April 4, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0179)
- Studs Terkel: "Telling It Like It Is," Boulder, Colorado, April 8, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0180)
- John Tirman: "Spoils of War: The Cost of America's Arms Trade," Boulder, Colorado, April 9, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0181)
- Danny Schechter: "The More You Watch, The Less You Know," Taos, New Mexico, April 18, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0182)
- Jeremy Brecher: "Labor in the Age of Globalization," New York, New York, April 30, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0183)
- Ross Gelbspan: "Global Warming: The Heat Is On," Portland, Oregon, May 4, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0184)
- Noam Chomsky: "U.S. Human Rights Policy: Rhetoric and Practice," Longmont, Colorado, May 10, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0185)
- Michael Shuman: "Going Local: Self-Reliant Communities," Washington, DC, May 13, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0292)
- Ralph Nader: "Renewable Energy," Amherst, Wisconsin, June 20, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0290)
- Howard Zinn: "U.S. Imperialism and The War with Spain," Cambridge, Massachusetts, June 30, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0186)
- Richard Grossman: "Challenging Corporate Power," Provincetown, Massachusetts, August 23, 1998
  - Audio recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0187)
  - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0281)
- Herbert Kohl: "The Creation of Hope in Public Education," New York, New York, September 1, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0188)
- Robert McChesney: "Corporate Media and the Threat to Democracy," Eau Claire, Wisconsin, September 14, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0289)
- Sister Helen Prejean: "Death Row: Into the Belly of the Beast," Gainesville, Florida, September 17, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0285)
- Alexander Cockburn: "The CIA, Drugs and the Media," Madison, Wisconsin, September 30, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0189)
- Benjamin Barber: "McWorld and the Free Market's Threat to Civic Culture," Boulder, Colorado, October 7, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0260)
- Eqbal Ahmad: "Terrorism: Theirs and Ours," Boulder, Colorado, October 12, 1998
  - Audio recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0190)
  - Audio recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0238)
- Dan Schiller: "Digital Capitalism," Boulder, Colorado, October 28, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0203)
- Marilyn Waring: "Hidden Economic Indicators," East Lansing, Michigan, October 30, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0288)
- Denis Halliday: "Sanctions in Iraq: A Human Rights Catastrophe," Cambridge, Massachusetts, November 5, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0191)
- Eric Foner: "The Struggle for Freedom," Salem, Oregon, November 5, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0284)
- David Korten: "Post-Corporate World," Edmonton, Alberta, November 12, 1998 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0252)
- William Greider: "Fortress America: The Military Industrial Complex," Washington, D.C., December 7, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0194)
- Diane Dujon: "Women, Welfare and Poverty," Bronxville, New York, December 8, 1998 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0193)
- Gary Webb: "CIA Crack Cocaine Connection," Eugene, Oregon, January 16, 1999 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0197)
- Bob Ortega: "The WalMarting of America," Boulder, Colorado, January 28, 1999 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0202)
- Michael Parenti: "The Sword and the Dollar," Vancouver, Washington, January 28, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0291)
- Noam Chomsky: "US Iraq Policy: Motives and Consequences," Cambridge, Massachusetts, January 30, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0286)
- Cornel West: "The Legacy of Paul Robeson," New York, New York, February 5, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0268)
- Phoebe Schellenberg: "Home Economics: The Sweat Off Her Brow," Boulder, Colorado, February 8, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0253)
- Helena Norberg-Hodge: "Resisting Monoculture, Rebuilding Community," San Francisco, California, February 23, 1999 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0195)
- Sydney Schanberg: "Sleaze Journalism: Decline and Fall of the Press," New York, New York, March 3, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0287)
- Kevin Danaher: "Corporate Accounting vs. Corporate Accountability," Boulder, Colorado, March 11, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0251)
- Stephen Zunes: "Myths of US Middle East Policy," Boulder, Colorado, March 16, 1999 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0192)
- Bill McKibben: "Livable Cities: Creating Sustainable Urban Environments," Boulder, Colorado, April 1, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0254)
- Israel Charny: "Genocide Denial," Berkeley, California, April 5, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0276)
- Howard Lyman: "Mad Vegetarian Cowboy," Boulder, Colorado, April 7, 1999 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0201)
- Susan Douglas: "Media Representations of Women," Taos, New Mexico, April 16, 1999 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0196)
- Stuart Ewen: "Public Relations: Corporate Spin and Propaganda," Taos, New Mexico, April 17, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0261)
- Susan Douglas: "Talk Radio: Letting Boys Be Boys," Taos, New Mexico, April 17, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0271)
- Martin Espada: "Zapata's Disciple," Venice, California, May 16, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0275)
- Michael Parenti: "The U.S. War on Yugoslavia," Seattle, Washington, May 16, 1999 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0198)
- Helen Caldicott: "Why to Care about Y2K?" Hopland, California, June 26, 1999 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0200)
- Britt Bailey and Marc Lappe: "Frankenfood: Genetically Modified Cuisine," Gualala, California, August 28, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0266)
- Chuck Collins and Holly Sklar: "Shifting Fortunes," Boston, Massachusetts, September 16, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0262)
- Edward Said: "Unresolved Geographies, Embattled Landscapes," Amherst, Massachusetts, September 17, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0259)
- Christian Parenti: "Lockdown America: The Growth of the Police State," Santa Monica, California, September 26, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0270)
- Charlie Kernaghan: "The Human Face of the Global Economy," Seattle, Washington, October 3, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0258)
- Noam Chomsky: "Globalization: The New Face of Capitalism," Chestnut Hill, Massachusetts, October 7, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0257)
- Jim Hightower: "Election 2000: A Space Odyssey," Colorado Springs, Colorado, November 11, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0267)
- Angela Davis: "Race, Crime and Punishment," Madison, Wisconsin, November 16, 1999
  - Original recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0204)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0302)
- Robin Hahnel: "Beyond Seattle: What Is To Be Done," Olympia, Washington, December 3, 1999 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0265)
- Father Roy Bourgeois: "School of the Assassins," Santa Barbara, California, January 14, 2000 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0273)
- Maude Barlow and Chee Yoke Ling: "Corporate Designed Food," Montreal, Quebec, January 22, 2000 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0272)
- Jeremy Rifkin: "Genetic Engineering," Montreal, Quebec, January 22, 2000 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0274)
- Frances Fox Piven: "The Politics of the Rich and Poor," Eugene, Oregon, February 29, 2000 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0242)
- Alicia Littletree: "Who Bombed Judi Bari?" Boulder, Colorado, May 5, 2000 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0240)
- Zinn, Abunimah, Arnove, Masri: "Iraq Under Siege," New York, New York, October 4, 2000 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0241)
- Frances Moore Lappe: "Restoring the Planet," Eugene, Oregon, November 4, 2000 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0227)
- Ward Churchill: "Big Brother is Watching," Washington, D.C., January 27, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0231)
- Arundhati Roy: "A Writer's Place in Politics," Amherst, Massachusetts, February 15, 2001
  - Audio recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0205)
  - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0250)
- Dana Frank: "Workers and the Challenge of Globalization," Eugene, Oregon, April 10, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0239)
- Frances Fox Piven: "Welfare Reform Revisited," New York, New York, April 13, 2001
  - Audio recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0217)
  - Audio recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0220)
- Noam Chomsky: "U.S. to U.N.: Do It Our Way," Cambridge, Massachusetts, April 17, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0235)
- Christopher Hitchens: "The Kissinger Case," Portland, Oregon, April 18, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0237)
- David Korten: "From Corporate Rule to Civil Society," Seattle, Washington, May 15, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0221)
- Helen Caldicott: "Desparate Passions and Direct Actions," Boulder, Colorado, May 18, 2001
  - Audio recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0218)
  - Audio recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0219)
- P. Sainath: "India and Market Fundamentalism," Cambridge, Massachusetts, June 5, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0215)
- Ron Daniels: "The Wrong Complexion to Get the Protection," Woods Hole, Massachusetts, June 9, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0224)
- Ronnie Dugger: "Reclaiming Democracy," Framingham, Massachusetts, June 19, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0248)
- Vandana Shiva: "Monocultures of the Mind," Santa Fe, New Mexico, June 30, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0226)
- Maude Barlow, Vandana Shiva and Tony Clarke: "Liquid Assets," Vancouver, British Columbia, July 5, 2001 (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0206)
- John Robbins: "The Food Revolution," Boulder, Colorado, August 22, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0214)
- Edward Said: "Origins of Terrorism", September 24, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0236)
- Howard Zinn: "Artists in a Time of War," Boston, Massachusetts, October 1, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0230)
- Nasim Zehra: "Afghanistan, bin Laden, and the Taliban," Boulder, Colorado, October 2, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0228)
- Noam Chomsky: "The New War on Terrorism," Cambridge, Massachusetts, October 18, 2001
  - Original recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0209)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0303)
- Ira Chernus: "9/11 and the National Insecurity State," Boulder, Colorado, October 18, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0229)
- Bruce Gagnon: "Beyond Star Wars," Eugene, Oregon, October 21, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0222)
- Esmail Nooriala: "The Multicultural Middle East," Boulder, Colorado, October 31, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0234)
- Michael Parenti: "Globalization and Imperialism," Columbus, Ohio, November 10, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0225)
- Pervez Hoodbhoy: "Pakistan, Islam and the U.S.," Cambridge, Massachusetts, November 16, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0210)
- Ira Glasser: "Patriotism, Civil Liberties and Terrorism," Santa Barbara, California, December 3, 2001 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0244)
- Ralph Nader: "Crashing the Party," Bothell, Washington, January 23, 2002 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0246)
- Charlotte Ryan: "Prime Time Activism," Cambridge, Massachusetts, January 28, 2002 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0247)
- Howard Zinn: "Emma Goldman, Anarchism and War Resistance," Cambridge, Massachusetts, January 29, 2002 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0245)
- John Ikerd: "Sustainable Agriculture," College City, Pennsylvania, February 8, 2002 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0232)
- Angela Davis: "Race, Power and Prisons Since Sept 11," Denver, Colorado, March 1, 2002 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0249)
- Michael Moore: "Stupid White Men," Boulder, Colorado, March 9, 2002 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0233)
- Norman Solomon: "Orwellian Media," Boulder, Colorado, April 8, 2002
  - Original recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0269)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0304)
- Barbara Bernstein: "The Malling of America: Across the Great Divide", undated
  - Part one (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0255)
  - Part two (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0256)
- "Carefully Taught: Clashing Values in the Classroom", undated
  - Part one (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0211)
  - Part two (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0212)
- Ed Dorn: "Satirical Verses", undated (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0277)
- Mumia Abu-Jamal: "A Case for Reasonable Doubt?", undated (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0208)
- "Return to the Nuclear Crossroads: Protest and Resistance at Rocky Flats", undated
  - Part one (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0207)
  - Part two (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0213)
  - Part one (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0279)
  - Part two (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0280)